Yumi's Cells 2
유미의 세포들 2
Professional Translator Work-related conversation: The person in charge isn't here ... I'll take that into consideration next time. What I really think: It's none of my business. I won't do it this time.
전문 번역가 업무 관련 대화: 담당자가 안 계시네요.. 그건 다음에 고려하겠습니다. 내가 실제로 생각하는 것: 그건 내 알 바가 아니다. 이번에는 안 할 거예요.
Episode 24 Professional Business Meeting
24화 전문적인 비즈니스 미팅
Editor-in-Chief Ahn Dae Yong: Writer Yumi
안대용 편집장 : 유미 작가
Editor-in-Chief Ahn Dae Yong: I'll do my best to select one. Please do your best to edit. I'll contact you when it's decided.
안대용 편집장: 최선을 다해 하나를 선택하겠습니다. 최선을 다해 편집해 주시기 바랍니다. 결정되면 연락드리겠습니다.
Writer Yumi.
작가 유미.
We have chosen someone to do the web novel illustrations.
웹소설 일러스트를 담당하실 분을 선정했습니다.
Really? (heart is pounding)
정말? (심장이 두근두근)
The illustrator will also be coming to the meeting on Wednesday.
일러스트레이터도 수요일 회의에 참석할 예정입니다.
All right, I got it.
알겠습니다. 알겠습니다.
Green Syndrome
녹색 증후군
- Hello.
- 안녕하세요.
This is Control Z, the illustrator who will illustrate your work from now on.
앞으로 여러분의 작품을 그려주실 일러스트레이터 Control Z 입니다.
Hello, I am Control Z.
안녕하세요 컨트롤Z입니다.
- Control Ji... - Z.
- 컨트롤 지... - Z.
- Sorry?
- 죄송합니다?
Z
Z
Oh, the letter Z. Control + Z
아, 문자 Z. Control + Z
What's with his pen name?
그의 필명은 무엇입니까?
Control Z.
Z를 제어하세요.
It's rude to laugh after hearing someone's pen name.
누군가의 필명을 듣고 웃는 것은 무례합니다.
Go! Go home and laugh all you want!
가다! 집에 가서 마음껏 웃으세요!
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
미안해요, 미안해요, 미안해요.
It's really rude to do that when you first meet someone.
누군가를 처음 만났을 때 그런 짓을 하는 것은 정말 무례한 일입니다.
You have to hold it in!
참아야 해!
You know the Control-Z keyboard shortcut? He says it stands for that.
Control-Z 키보드 단축키를 아시나요? 그는 그것이 그것을 의미한다고 말합니다.
Everyone calls him Con Ji.
다들 그를 콘지라고 부른다.
Con Z, not Con Ji.
콘지가 아니라 콘Z.
I see.
알겠어요.
Nice to meet you, I am Kim Yumi.
반갑습니다 김유미 입니다.
- Have a seat. - All right.
- 자리에 앉으세요. - 괜찮은.
He is the illustrator who worked on the covers of our book series.
그는 우리 책 시리즈의 표지를 작업한 일러스트레이터입니다.
This time we went to a lot of effort to ask him and were barely able to get him—
이번에 우리는 그에게 물어보려고 많은 노력을 기울였지만 간신히 구할 수 있었습니다.
Sorry.
죄송합니다.
I need to take this call.
이 전화를 받아야 해요.
Yes, this is Ahn Dae Yong.
네, 안대용입니다.
I really liked the cover of that series.
나는 그 시리즈의 표지를 정말 좋아했습니다.
Of course, you did.
물론 그렇습니다.
- Is that the new manuscript? - Yes.
- 그게 새 원고인가요? - 예.
Can I read it?
읽어도 될까요?
Yes, of course. I brought it for the two of you anyway.
물론이죠. 어쨌든 너희 둘을 위해 가져왔어.
Oh, I will go get it.
아, 내가 가서 사올게.
He's unusual. Even his name is unusual.
그는 특이해요. 그의 이름조차 특이하다.
His personality also seems unusual.
성격도 특이한 것 같아요.
Please enjoy.
즐겨주세요.
You ordered an iced latte, correct?
아이스라떼 주문하셨죠?
♫ Yeah ♫
♫ 응 ♫
He just laughed, is there a funny part?
그냥 웃었는데, 웃긴 부분이 있나요?
Did you find it?
찾았나요?
What did that snort just now mean?
방금 그 코웃음은 무슨 뜻이었나요?
That snort is the sound that comes out unknowingly even though one had no intention of laughing.
그 콧소리는 웃을 의도가 전혀 없는데도 자신도 모르게 나오는 소리다.
Huh, then ...
응, 그럼...
That just now ...
지금 막...
was him cracking up.
그 사람이 화를 내고 있었나요?
This version must be fun!
이 버전은 재미있을 것 같아요!
Thank you, I finished reading.
감사합니다. 다 읽었습니다.
It still needs some polishing, but what did you think of the manuscript?
아직 다듬기가 좀 필요한데, 원고에 대해 어떻게 생각하시나요?
How should I put it?
어떻게 넣어야 할까요?
This genre is definitely
이 장르는 확실히
not my type.
내 타입은 아니야.
Should I say it is zero reality?
현실 제로라고 해야 하나?
Reality zero?
현실 제로?
Then the snort wasn't because it was funny!
그렇다면 콧소리는 재미있어서가 아니었습니다!
It seems so...
그런 것 같아요...
Then what was that snort?
그럼 그 코웃음은 뭐였지?
According to my new analysis,
나의 새로운 분석에 따르면,
I think it was a sound that came out because of how absurdly unrealistic it was.
너무 황당할 정도로 비현실적이어서 나온 소리였던 것 같아요.
What?
무엇?
No matter how unrealistic it was, saying it is a bit too much.
아무리 비현실적이라 해도 좀 지나친 것 같다.
Writer! It makes me upset hearing that it's too unrealistic.
작가! 너무 비현실적이라는 말을 들으니 속상하네요.
Am I the weird one?
내가 이상한 사람인가요?
No, you're normal.
아니, 당신은 정상이에요.
That's completely rude to say to the writer!
작가에게 그런 말을 하는 건 정말 무례한 일이에요!
Right?
오른쪽?
Being upset after hearing that is normal, right?!
그 말을 듣고 속상한 건 당연한 거겠죠?!
But... - One second.
하지만... - 1초만요.
This is a professional business meeting.
전문적인 비즈니스 미팅입니다.
You worked at a company for a long time, so you should know that.
회사에서 오래 일했으니 그걸 알아야 해요.
When you work, you meet all kinds of people, right?
일하다 보면 온갖 종류의 사람들을 만나죠?
Yes, that's true.
네, 맞습니다.
It's something you have to just cooly laugh at and move on from.
그것은 당신이 냉정하게 웃고 넘어가야 할 일입니다.
You guys go ahead and be cool about it!
여러분, 가서 침착하게 행동하세요!
But ... which part is unrealistic?
그런데... 어떤 부분이 비현실적인가요?
I just informally gave my opinion.
나는 단지 비공식적으로 내 의견을 말했을 뿐이다.
Did it make you uncomfortable?
불편하게 만들었나요?
What is he saying now?
그 사람 지금 무슨 말을 하는 거지?
Unintelligible
이해할 수 없음
- Seriously. - That jerk.
- 진지하게. - 그 멍청이.
He seems to be polite,
그 사람은 예의바른 것 같아,
but he's just the opposite.
하지만 그는 정반대다.
In other words, what he means is this:
즉, 그가 의미하는 바는 다음과 같습니다.
I just informally gave my opinion.
나는 단지 비공식적으로 내 의견을 말했을 뿐이다.
- Are you - pissed off?
- 당신은요? - 화났어?
Of course not, feel free to tell me.
물론 그렇지 않습니다. 자유롭게 말씀해 주십시오.
What part made you feel that it was unrealistic?
어떤 부분에서 비현실적이라고 느꼈나요?
First, I think the couples from here are too honest with each other.
우선 여기 커플들은 서로에게 너무 솔직한 것 같아요.
I told you it's unrealistic.
나는 그것이 비현실적이라고 말했습니다.
- Is that so? - Yes, a little bit.
- 그렇습니까? - 네, 조금요.
Completely unrealistic.
완전히 비현실적입니다.
It's not actually like that in reality.
실제로는 그렇지 않습니다.
You haven't dated, have you, kid?
넌 데이트한 적 없지, 꼬마야?
I tried to let it go and move on,
나는 그것을 놓아두고 계속 나아가려고 노력했다.
but this isn't right.
하지만 이건 옳지 않아요.
We are professionals. Let's turn this around like a professional.
우리는 전문가입니다. 전문가처럼 이 문제를 해결해 보겠습니다.
I'm not so sure about that. In my experience, that isn't the case.
나는 그것에 대해 잘 모르겠습니다. 내 경험에 의하면 그렇지 않습니다.
Is there something you don't know?
당신이 모르는 뭔가가 있나요?
You haven't dated, have you, kid?
넌 데이트한 적 없지, 꼬마야?
I'm in a relationship.
나는 연애 중이에요.
Couldn't the standard for judging whether it's unrealistic or not
비현실적인지 아닌지를 판단하는 기준이 없나요
come down to a difference in experience?
경험의 차이로 귀결되나요?
Well. Since everyone has different experiences.
잘. 사람마다 경험이 다르기 때문이죠.
And you're the only one who's like that.
그리고 그런 사람은 당신뿐이에요.
You're the only one who's like that.
당신은 그런 유일한 사람입니다.
Good job. That was calm, sophisticated, and mature.
잘했어요. 차분하고, 세련되고, 성숙했어요.
Well, that's true, it would be different for everyone.
글쎄요, 그건 사실입니다. 사람마다 다를 것입니다.
Then I guess you must be the kind of person who's always honest when dating?
그렇다면 당신은 연애할 때 항상 솔직한 성격이 아닐까?
Always? 100%?
언제나? 100%?
Wow, you're amazing.
와, 정말 대단해요.
That an always, 100% honest relationship is possible.
항상 100% 정직한 관계가 가능하다는 것.
You're shameless.
당신은 뻔뻔해요.
- I mean— - I'm envious, that's all.
- 내 말은- - 부럽다, 그뿐이다.
I hope that I can also have such a relationship once in my life.
나도 일생에 한 번은 그런 인연을 가질 수 있었으면 좋겠다.
The coffee is good.
커피는 좋다.
You're shameless.
당신은 뻔뻔해요.
and your manuscript,
그리고 당신의 원고,
completely unrealistic.
완전히 비현실적입니다.
Game over.
게임이 끝났습니다.
- All right. - That's okay.
- 괜찮은. - 괜찮아요.
Sorry, the phone call took a while.
죄송합니다. 전화 통화에 시간이 좀 걸렸습니다.
Were you able to discuss a lot?
많은 이야기를 나눌 수 있었나요?
Yes, well.
네, 글쎄요.
I respect Illustrator Control Z's opinion.
저는 Illustrator Control Z의 의견을 존중합니다.
However, he hasn't experienced everything that others have, has he?
하지만 그는 다른 사람들이 겪는 모든 것을 경험한 것은 아니지요?
It's a very dangerous idea to conclude that
It's a very dangerous idea to conclude that
everything you've never experienced is unrealistic.
당신이 경험하지 못한 모든 것은 비현실적입니다.
That is what you call prejudice.
그것이 바로 편견이라고 하는 것입니다.
Above all, I don't think it's right to entrust the illustration of my work
무엇보다도 제 작품의 일러스트를 맡기는 것은 옳지 않다고 생각해요
to someone who thinks my work is unrealistic.
내 작업이 비현실적이라고 생각하는 사람에게.
In conclusion, this is what I want to say!
결론적으로 내가 하고 싶은 말은 이것이다!
You're
당신은
out.
밖으로.
Would you stop worrying about something that's already happened and go?
이미 일어난 일에 대해 걱정하지 말고 가실래요?
It's time for Yumi to sleep.
이제 유미가 잠잘 시간이에요.
Seriously! I should have said 'You're out, out!' right then.
진지하게! 나는 '너는 아웃이야, 아웃이야!'라고 말했어야 했어. 바로 그때.
What a rude brat!
정말 무례한 놈이군요!
We'll see if he can even draw well, damn it.
그가 그림을 잘 그릴 수 있는지 알아보겠습니다. 젠장.
Writer, hello.
작가님, 안녕하세요.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
I see you got here early.
일찍 오셨나 보군요.
Yes, a little.
네, 조금요.
Professional business meetings continue, no matter how much you hate them.
아무리 싫어해도 전문적인 비즈니스 미팅은 계속됩니다.
A Hawaiian coffee for me, please.
하와이안 커피 주세요.
Could I have a milk tea, please?
밀크티 한잔 주시겠어요?
And one castella for me.
그리고 나한테는 카스텔라 하나.
Sensitivity: What? Why is he only ordering one?
민감도: 뭐? 그 사람은 왜 하나만 주문하는 걸까요?
We have a mouth too!
우리에게도 입이 있다!
- Hunger: Order it! Order it! Order it for us too! - Sure.
- 배고픔: 주문하세요! 주문하세요! 우리에게도 주문해주세요! - 확신하는.
Just a second, please.
잠시만 기다려 주세요.
Would you like to order something?
뭔가 주문하시겠습니까?
The castella here is delicious, order that.
여기 카스텔라 맛있으니 꼭 주문하세요.
No, I don't like it.
아니요, 마음에 들지 않습니다.
I absolutely don't want to eat what that jerk recommends.
나는 그 멍청이가 추천하는 것을 절대 먹고 싶지 않습니다.
I'm telling you the castella is delicious.
카스텔라가 맛있다고 하던데.
Recommended: Castella
추천: 카스텔라
I'll have a ginger pie, please.
생강 파이 주세요.
Sure.
확신하는.
You deliberately ordered something different.
일부러 다른 걸 주문하셨어요.
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
I've always liked ginger pie.
나는 항상 생강 파이를 좋아했습니다.
The ginger pie here really doesn't taste good.
여기 생강파이는 정말 맛이 없어요.
Watch what you say about whatever I ordered!
내가 주문한 것에 대해 당신이 말하는 것을 조심하십시오!
You! Have you ever said one kind thing to anyone?
너! 누군가에게 친절한 말을 한 적이 있습니까?
You thoughtless jerk!
이 생각없는 멍청이!
- What is it? - It's nothing.
- 그게 뭐죠? - 아무것도 아니야.
Take a look at this scene, please.
이 장면을 한번 봐주세요.
The situation and the picture don't match.
상황과 그림이 일치하지 않습니다.
They haven't met in a long time, so it's a very heart-fluttering situation, but take a look here.
오랜만에 만난 두 사람이라 너무 설렘이 가득한 상황인데, 한 번 살펴보세요.
These eyes.
이 눈.
Aren't the man's eyes too sunken in?
남자 눈이 너무 푹 들어간거 아냐?
Rather than being heart-fluttering, his expression looks as if he's bored and wants to go home.
설렘보다는 심심해 집에 가고 싶은 표정이다.
I think it needs fixing.
제 생각엔 고쳐야 할 것 같아요.
Oh, also, if you look at the next scene.
아, 그리고 다음 장면을 보면.
It's a situation that needs to show the main character's sincerity,
주인공의 진심을 보여줘야 하는 상황인데,
but it's far from it ...
하지만 그것과는 거리가 멀다...
Hunger: Yuck! What's wrong with this?
배고픔: 윽! 이게 무슨 문제야?
It tastes so bad!
맛이 너무 나빠요!
This is crazy! It tastes like trash!
이건 미친 짓이야! 쓰레기 같은 맛이 나네요!
Sensitivity: Hey! Won't you be quiet? Just deal with it and eat it.
민감도: 이봐! 조용히 하지 않을래? 그냥 처리하고 먹습니다.
Pretend it's delicious!
맛있는 척!
Writer Yumi.
작가 유미.
Eat mine. You said you liked ginger pie.
내 것을 먹어라. 당신은 생강 파이를 좋아한다고 했어요.
Ginger.
생강.
I was right, wasn't I?
내가 옳았지, 그렇지?
See? Didn't I tell you the ginger pie was disgusting?
보다? 내가 생강파이가 역겹다고 말하지 않았나요?
No, it's good.
아니요, 좋습니다.
This is good?
이거 좋은데?
Wow, your taste buds are really stubborn.
와, 당신 입맛은 정말 고집스럽군요.
You're shameless.
당신은 뻔뻔해요.
Also, they say ginger is good for colds.
그리고 감기에도 생강이 좋다고 하더라고요.
- I was feeling a cold coming on, so this turned out well. - You caught a cold? A c-cold?
- 감기가 오는 것 같아서 잘 됐어요. - 감기에 걸렸나요? 감기?
Why didn't you tell me sooner?
왜 더 일찍 말하지 않았나요?
I mean, it's not serious. My body is just slightly ...
즉, 심각한 것은 아니다. 몸이 좀...
You didn't put your fork on the castella, did you?
카스텔라에 포크를 올려 놓지 않았죠?
- I didn't. - Thank goodness.
- 안 그랬어요. - 맙소사.
I came thinking you had gotten off work, but you weren't home, so I just left these.
퇴근하신 줄 알고 왔는데 집에 없으셔서 그냥 두고 가셨어요.
The golden oranges from our farm grew well.
우리 농장의 황금 오렌지가 잘 자랐습니다.
Please enjoy! Da Eun said she is doing well.
즐겨주세요! 다은이는 잘 지내고 있다고 하더군요.
Thank you for looking after Da Eun.
다은이를 돌봐주셔서 감사합니다.
Da Eun's mom.
다은의 엄마.
- Yumi! - Ba Bi! Did you get off work?
- 유미! - 바비! 퇴근하셨어요?
Yeah, I just got home.
응, 방금 집에 왔어.
- But what's with your expression? - Why?
-근데 표정이 어때요? - 왜?
- You look really tired. - Yeah, I am tired. Like I said, I just got home.
- 정말 피곤해 보여요. - 응, 피곤해. 내가 말했듯이, 나는 방금 집에 도착했습니다.
But where are you?
그런데 당신은 어디에 있나요?
- I'm waiting for the bus after finishing a meeting. - But what's with your expression?
- 회의를 마치고 버스를 기다리고 있어요. -근데 표정이 어때요?
- Why? - It looks like you've been through hell.
- 왜? - 지옥을 겪은 것 같군요.
I'm completely exhausted.
나는 완전히 지쳤습니다.
I'm exhausted because I had a meeting with someone I hate so much.
너무 싫은 사람과 미팅을 해서 지쳤어요.
- Are you talking about that illustrator? - Yes.
- 그 일러스트레이터 말씀이신가요? - 예.
It was nice when I was unemployed. As expected, I don't like the people
실직했을 때 좋았거든요. 역시 난 사람이 싫어
I meet through work.
나는 일을 통해 만난다.
Can't you ask them to change the illustrator?
일러스트레이터 바꿔달라고 하면 안되나요?
It's too late. And he draws well.
너무 늦었어요. 그리고 그는 그림을 잘 그립니다.
I see. Then you have to put up with it.
알겠어요. 그렇다면 참아야합니다.
I do. But ...
그래요. 하지만...
he's so, so, so annoying.
그 사람 정말 너무 너무 짜증나.
I mean, earlier he made me so annoyed just with one cake.
내 말은, 아까 그 사람이 케이크 하나만으로 나를 너무 짜증나게 만들었단 말이에요.
He ordered just one castella for himself, even though I was hungry too.
나 역시 배고픈데도 그는 카스텔라 하나만 주문했다.
And when she came home.
그리고 그녀가 집에 왔을 때.
What is this?
이게 뭔가요?
♫ I spend the day constantly acting fearless ♫
♫ 나는 끊임없이 두려움 없이 행동하며 하루를 보낸다 ♫
♫ and before I know it ♫
♫ 그리고 나도 모르게 ♫
♫ the night arrives ♫
♫ 밤이 다가온다 ♫
♫ The dark night ♫
♫ 어두운 밤 ♫
♫ The sadness which I've endured all day ♫
♫ 하루종일 견뎌온 슬픔 ♫
- Hello? - Ba Bi!
- 안녕하세요? - 바비!
- Did you send me the cakes? - Did it already arrive?
- 나한테 케이크 보냈어? - 벌써 도착했어요?
Eat whichever one you like, in place of that ginger pie.
그 생강 파이 대신에 당신이 좋아하는 것을 먹어라.
Ba Bi,
바비,
thank you.
감사합니다.
Who cares about Control Z.
Control Z에 관심 있는 사람
We received this kind of gift!
우리는 이런 선물을 받았습니다!
And we have a boyfriend who gives this kind of gift!
그리고 우리에겐 이런 선물을 주는 남자친구도 있어요!
One second.
1초.
- Yumi! - Ba Bi!
- 유미! - 바비!
Eat it all by yourself, don't give any to anyone else!
남한테 주지 말고 혼자 다 먹어요!
Okay. I miss you, Ba Bi.
좋아요. 보고 싶어, 바비.
I miss you too.
나도 보고 싶어요.
And we are in a lovey-dovey relationship like this.
그리고 우리는 이렇게 러브러브 관계에 있습니다.
When you combine all this,
이 모든 것을 결합하면
its bragging worth is over level 99!
자랑할만한 가치는 레벨 99 이상입니다!
If it's at this rate, then it's equivalent to bragging about the trip to Thailand.
이대로라면 태국 여행을 자랑하는 셈이다.
Upload it on social media immediately!
즉시 SNS에 업로드해주세요!
Yahoo! Cake. Surprise gift.
야후! 케이크. 깜짝 선물.
The fun of eating whichever I want. Thank you, Ba Bi.
먹고 싶은 대로 먹는 재미. 고마워요, 바비.
The ginger pie must have been a shock.
생강 파이는 충격이었을 것입니다.
You've got enough to last you until next year.
내년까지 버틸 수 있을 만큼 충분합니다.
The cakes are so pretty! It must be delicious.
케이크가 너무 예뻐요! 맛있을 것 같아요.
I'm so jealous, Writer Kim! I'm going to eat some.
부럽습니다 김 작가님! 나는 좀 먹을거야.
- Ha ha ha ha ha. - What are you doing there?
- 하하하하하. - 거기서 뭐해요?
Hello. I'm Control Z. Z.
안녕하세요. 저는 Control Z.Z입니다.
Why are you here?
당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까?
More than that, it's not even a funny picture.
게다가 웃기는 사진도 아니다.
What's with the 'ha ha ha ha ha'?
'하하하하하'는 무슨 뜻인가요?
I'll explain it to you. It's all in this book.
제가 설명해 드리겠습니다. 이 책에 모두 나와 있습니다.
Explaining The Ha
하를 설명하다
A book that compiles the different meanings of 'ha' in various situations.
다양한 상황에서 '하'의 다양한 의미를 모아놓은 책.
One 'ha' used on a picture that isn't even funny means it is a snort.
재미도 없는 사진에 사용된 '하'는 콧방귀라는 뜻입니다.
Two ha's: Ha ha. It means, "I have nothing to say."
두 하의: 하하. "할 말이 없다"는 뜻이다.
Five ha's: Hahahahaha.
5ha: 하하하하하.
It means they're 100% laughing at us.
그것은 그들이 100% 우리를 비웃고 있다는 것을 의미합니다.
What is it? Why are you laughing at me?
그것은 무엇입니까? 왜 나를 비웃나요?
Who do you think you are?
당신은 누구라고 생각합니까?
Call Profanity cell!
욕설 세포에 전화하세요!
Profanity cell. Currently serving a life sentence in prison.
욕설 세포. 현재 감옥에서 종신형을 선고받고 복역 중이다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Hey b*tch! It's been a f*cking long time.
이봐 개년아! 정말 오랜 시간이 걸렸습니다.
Yumi is f*cking looking for me? Is that f*cking true?
유미가 나를 찾고 있다고? 그게 사실이야?
That's right. Go on, swear a lot.
좋아요. 어서, 많이 맹세하세요.
Sensitivity, you crazy b*tch!
민감해, 이 미친년아!
Not to me!
나한테는 안 돼!
To Control Z.
Z를 제어하려면
I'm f*cking sorry. You should have told me earlier. F*ck . I didn't know.
정말 미안해요. 좀 더 일찍 말했어야 했는데. 젠장 . 나는 몰랐다.
What is it, you f*cking b*stard?
그게 뭐야, 이 빌어먹을 새끼야?
Why are you laughing at me, you annoying b*stard?
왜 나를 비웃느냐, 짜증나는 새끼야?
I can't stand it. I think I need to write something.
나는 그것을 참을 수 없다. 뭔가 써야 할 것 같아요.
Wait. He's someone you met through work and you are a new writer.
기다리다. 그 사람은 직장에서 만난 사람이고, 당신은 신인 작가예요.
It can be fatal to your reputation.
이는 귀하의 평판에 치명적일 수 있습니다.
Let's not forget! This is a professional business meeting.
잊지 말자! 전문적인 비즈니스 미팅입니다.
That's right. I'm the only one who looks foolish when I get angry rashly.
좋아요. 성급하게 화를 내면 어리석어 보이는 건 나뿐이다.
Reply
답장
In professional business meetings, you can't use crude curse words.
전문적인 비즈니스 미팅에서는 거친 욕설을 사용할 수 없습니다.
However ...
그러나...
any employee should always keep in mind that this
모든 직원은 항상 다음을 명심해야 합니다
may be the worst curse you can send to another person.
다른 사람에게 보낼 수 있는 최악의 저주일 수도 있습니다.
[yumii_0109] [ -_- ]
[yumii_0109] [ -_- ]
Episode 25 Things Yumi hate
25화 유미가 싫어하는 것
Hello. I am Dislike cell.
안녕하세요. 나는 싫어하는 세포입니다.
I manage all the things that Yumi hates.
유미가 싫어하는 건 다 제가 관리해요.
Things like this ... I love it.
이런 것들은... 정말 좋아요.
I can smell the toner from your scarf. I love it.
스카프에서 토너 냄새가 나네요. 나는 그것을 좋아한다.
But from some point on, Yumi didn't really hate many things,
그런데 어느 순간부터 유미는 별로 싫은 일이 많지 않게 됐고,
so I spend most of my time playing in the water or taking naps.
그래서 저는 대부분의 시간을 물놀이나 낮잠을 자면서 보냅니다.
But recently, something Yumi hates a lot has appeared.
그런데 최근 유미가 정말 싫어하는 게 나타났어요.
That is this guy!
바로 이 사람이에요!
- Z. - A person she hates. Charges: Bad Manners
- 지. - 싫어하는 사람. 혐의: 나쁜 매너
It's been a long time since someone she really hates appeared.
정말 싫어하는 사람이 나타난 건 오랜만이다.
Writer. How about Monday for the next meeting?
작가. 다음 회의가 있는 월요일은 어때요?
I'm going to Jeju Island. I'll be back at the beginning of the new year.
저는 제주도에 갑니다. 새해 초에 다시 돌아오겠습니다.
Jeju Island?
제주도?
Yes. I'll see you in the new year.
예. 새해에 뵙겠습니다.
Oh ...! I'm jealous.
오 ...! 나는 질투한다.
You are spending the end of the year holidays on Jeju Island.
연말 연휴를 제주도에서 보내고 계십니다.
Are you jealous? Then go on your own trip.
당신은 질투합니까? 그럼 당신만의 여행을 떠나보세요.
^^
^^
Using two smiling eyes on you is a waste.
웃는 두 눈을 당신에게 사용하는 것은 낭비입니다.
I hate him so much.
나는 그를 너무 싫어합니다.
I also have a temper. If you annoy me, I will start swearing.
나도 성질이 있어요. 나를 괴롭히면 욕을 시작하겠습니다.
♫ I only wanna be with you everyday ♫
♫ 난 단지 당신과 매일 같이 있고 싶어 ♫
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Ba Bi, I've just arrived and I'm on my way in a taxi.
바비야, 나 방금 도착해서 택시 타고 가는 중이야.
Of course, I also change according to the person I am with.
물론 나도 함께 있는 사람에 따라 변한다.
Yumi, the meeting has started now, so I'll call you later.
유미 씨, 이제 회의가 시작됐으니 나중에 전화할게요.
Okay, I'll text you as soon as I reach home. Bye.
알았어, 집에 도착하자마자 문자 보낼게. 안녕.
♫ Because it is you who welcomed timid me ♫
♫ 소심한 나를 반겨준 건 너니까 ♫
The second Christmas I'm spending with Ba Bi.
바비와 함께 보내는 두 번째 크리스마스.
This time we decided to stay in Jeju Island till New Year.
이번에 우리는 새해까지 제주도에 머물기로 결정했습니다.
♫ Everyday higher than the sky there ♫
♫ 매일 그곳의 하늘보다 높이 ♫
♫ I want my feelings to be ♫
♫ 내 감정이 ♫
♫ wholly delivered to you ♫
♫ 완전히 당신에게 전달되었습니다 ♫
♫ Awesome day if it becomes your day ♫
♫ 그것이 당신의 하루가 된다면 멋진 하루 ♫
♫ so you can always smile ♫
♫ 항상 웃을 수 있도록 ♫
♫ and clear your clouds away ♫
♫ 그리고 구름을 걷어내세요 ♫
♫ Everyday ♫
♫ 매일 ♫
The kitchen is a little disappointing. Besides that it is perfect.
주방이 조금 아쉽네요. 게다가 완벽해요.
Well, you aren't going to use it a lot.
글쎄, 당신은 그것을 많이 사용하지 않을 것입니다.
That's true, but my wife likes to cook.
그건 사실이에요. 하지만 제 아내는 요리하는 걸 좋아해요.
If it's just the two of you, that's more than enough.
둘만 있다면 그것만으로도 충분해요.
Who are you?
누구세요?
Why have you come here?
왜 여기에 왔나요?
You must be the tenant's wife. Hello.
당신은 임차인의 아내여야 합니다. 안녕하세요.
No, I'm a friend.
아니요, 저는 친구입니다.
I see. We came to see the house.
알겠어요. 우리는 집을 보러 왔습니다.
I came after I talked with the tenant on the phone earlier.
아까 세입자와 통화하고 나서 왔습니다.
He let me know the front door passcode.
그는 나에게 현관 비밀번호를 알려주었다.
You came to see the house?
집 보러 오셨어요?
Yes. The tenant is giving up the house.
예. 임차인이 집을 포기하고 있습니다.
Just a minute.
잠시만요.
Hello? Did you get home?
안녕하세요? 집에 도착했어요?
- Yes. But did you give up the house? - Huh?
- 예. 그런데 집은 포기하셨나요? - 뭐?
I arrived and someone was seeing the house.
도착했는데 누군가 집을 보고 있었어요.
Oh, those people came already?
아, 그 사람들 벌써 왔나요?
- They said they'll come around five o'clock. - You're going to move?
- 5시쯤 온다고 하더군요. - 이사할 건가요?
- Yes. - Why?
- 예. - 왜?
I think I should move near the office.
사무실 근처로 이사해야 할 것 같아요.
I want to move to an apartment.
아파트로 이사하고 싶어요.
Why all of a sudden? You said you liked this house.
왜 갑자기? 이 집이 마음에 든다고 하셨어요.
At first, I did. But I think it's too far from the office.
처음에는 그랬어요. 그런데 사무실에서 너무 먼 것 같아요.
Also, commuting to and from work is too long.
또한, 출퇴근 시간도 너무 깁니다.
You said the morning and evening drive along the coast is a dream.
아침저녁으로 해안을 따라 드라이브하는 것이 꿈이라고 하더군요.
I did. But that was also for a few days only.
그랬어요. 하지만 그것도 며칠 동안뿐이었다.
A few of the employees live in the apartment in front of the office and they said it's really nice.
사무실 앞 아파트에 직원 몇 명이 살고 있는데 정말 좋다고 하더라구요.
The airport is close too.
공항도 가깝습니다.
I suppose.
아마도.
You should do what you want.
당신이 원하는 것을 해야 합니다.
But I like this house a lot. It's a shame.
그런데 나는 이 집이 너무 마음에 든다. 부끄러운 일이다.
There's a yard too.
마당도 있어요.
- Then, we'll get going. - Goodbye.
- 그럼 출발하겠습니다. - 안녕히 가세요.
I'm also taking a quick break. I have to go back in.
저도 잠깐 쉬고 있어요. 다시 들어가야 해요.
- I'll call you once I'm done. - All right. Bye.
- 끝나면 전화할게요. - 괜찮은. 안녕.
It's so nice.
정말 좋네요.
Then is this my last time here?
그럼 이번이 마지막이 되는 건가요?
That's a shame. Yumi liked it.
안타깝네요. 유미는 그것을 좋아했습니다.
But, isn't he moving very suddenly?
그런데 그 사람 너무 갑자기 움직이지 않나요?
He's moving out of the blue.
그는 갑자기 움직이고 있습니다.
He says the commute is really tough.
출퇴근길이 정말 힘들다고 하더군요.
Don't you remember just last week when he said driving to and from work is the happiest part of his day?
지난주에 그가 운전해서 출퇴근하는 것이 하루 중 가장 행복한 시간이라고 말한 것을 기억하지 않습니까?
It's weird. Why did he suddenly start disliking the happiest part of his day?
이상해요. 왜 그는 갑자기 하루 중 가장 행복한 시간을 싫어하기 시작했을까요?
- I'm not sure. - I think I know something.
- 잘 모르겠어요. - 뭔가 아는 것 같아요.
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
Recently, there's one missing element of that drive.
최근에 해당 드라이브에 누락된 요소가 하나 있습니다.
Da Eun.
다은.
There I go again.
또 간다.
Let's stop, Kim Yumi. Why are you being like a loser?
그만하자 김유미. 왜 패배자 같은 거야?
Nice! It's really pretty.
멋진! 정말 예쁘네요.
I should upload stuff like this on social media.
이런 것들을 소셜미디어에 올려야겠어요.
If I upload this, that Control Z jerk might laugh at me again.
내가 이걸 올리면 그 컨트롤Z 새끼가 또 날 비웃을지도 몰라.
Laugh at me again and I will get revenge on you very cruelly.
또 나를 비웃으면 아주 잔인하게 복수할 것이다.
It's done. It'll be perfect if I just go buy the cake.
끝났습니다. 그냥 케이크 사러 가면 딱 좋을 것 같아요.
Hello. Cake...
안녕하세요. 케이크...
Oh, this is pretty.
아, 이거 예쁘네요.
- I'll take the middle one. - Sure.
- 중간으로 하겠습니다. - 확신하는.
- Do you need candles too? - Yes. Give me two, please.
- 양초도 필요해요? - 예. 두 개 주세요.
Oh my god. It's visible from here too.
맙소사. 여기에서도 보입니다.
It changed the whole neighborhood's vibe.
동네 분위기 전체가 바뀌었어요.
Kim Yumi, you're sensible.
김유미, 당신은 센스가 있어요.
Miss Da Eun?
다은씨?
Hello, it's been a while.
안녕하세요, 오랜만입니다.
Oh, yes. Hello.
아, 그렇죠. 안녕하세요.
I heard you got a job at Busan.
부산에 취직했다고 들었어.
- You must have come home. - Yes, because of the holidays.
- 집에 오셨나봐요. - 네, 연휴 때문에요.
My mom asked me to come home.
엄마는 나에게 집에 오라고 하셨다.
I see.
알겠어요.
The Christmas tree is so pretty.
크리스마스 트리가 너무 예뻐요.
It's pretty, right? I decorated it.
예쁘죠? 나는 그것을 장식했다.
Yes, it's very pretty.
네, 정말 예뻐요.
It really feels like Christmas.
정말 크리스마스 같은 느낌이에요.
Is work fun?
일은 재미있나요?
Yes, well, it is fun.
네, 재미있습니다.
That's good.
좋아요.
Which company do you work at?
어느 회사에서 일하시나요?
I work for a logistics company. The head office is at the Busan port.
저는 물류회사에 다니고 있습니다. 본점은 부산항에 있다.
Oh, I see.
알겠어요.
- Something seems to have changed about Da Eun. - You're right. She has changed.
- 다은이는 뭔가 달라진 것 같아요. - 당신 말이 맞아요. 그녀는 변했습니다.
What changed?
무엇이 바뀌었나요?
She isn't able to meet our eyes?
그 사람이 우리 눈을 못 마주치나요?
Oh, right. I'm enjoying it.
아, 그렇죠. 나는 그것을 즐기고 있다.
- What? - Your web novel.
- 무엇? - 당신의 웹 소설.
Oh my. Really?
아, 이런. 정말?
Its only been a few weeks since it was published.
출간된 지 불과 몇 주밖에 되지 않았습니다.
I also turned on the notifications for it
나도 그것에 대한 알림을 켰어
and I've been reading it every Monday and Thursday morning.
매주 월요일과 목요일 아침에 그것을 읽고 있어요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Ah, but this is really embarrassing.
아 그런데 이거 정말 부끄럽네요.
It's really fun.
정말 재미있어요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
That's not it. She's fine now.
그게 아닙니다. 그녀는 이제 괜찮습니다.
She's meeting our eyes.
그녀가 우리와 눈을 마주쳤습니다.
- Then I'll get going. - Sure.
- 그럼 이만 갈게요. - 확신하는.
But it will be hard to see you now that Ba Bi is moving.
하지만 바비가 이사하는 지금은 만나기 힘들 것 같아요.
- What? - He's giving up the house.
- 무엇? - 그 사람은 집을 포기했어요.
He's moving to an apartment in the city.
그는 도시의 아파트로 이사할 예정이다.
- So now it will be really hard to see— - Why?
- 이제 정말 보기 힘들 것 같아요— - 왜요?
Is it because of me?
나 때문인가요?
What?
무엇?
Because of you, Miss Da Eun?
다은씨 때문에요?
Oh, I'm sorry!
아, 미안해요!
I'm suddenly remembering something from years ago.
갑자기 몇년전 일이 생각나네요.
Before she started dating Ba Bi and Wung.
Ba Bi와 Wung과 데이트를 시작하기 전.
We made a lot of dislikes with Yi Da when she was single.
이다가 싱글이었을 때 우리는 이다를 많이 싫어했습니다.
- Yumi. - Huh?
- 유미. - 뭐?
Let's say you have a boyfriend.
당신에게 남자친구가 있다고 가정해보자.
That won't happen.
그런 일은 일어나지 않을 것입니다.
Let's just say it happens.
그냥 그런 일이 발생한다고 가정 해 봅시다.
Imagine it. Anyway, you got a boyfriend.
상상해보세요. 어쨌든, 너 남자친구 생겼잖아.
That boyfriend still hasn't forgotten his ex.
그 남자친구는 아직도 전여친을 잊지 못하고 있어요.
What? I would totally hate that. Then we'd break up immediately.
무엇? 나는 그것을 완전히 싫어할 것입니다. 그러면 우리는 즉시 헤어질 것입니다.
Your boyfriend was swayed by someone else for just a moment.
당신의 남자친구는 한순간 다른 사람에게 휘둘렸을 뿐입니다.
But it was just a moment.
그러나 그것은 단지 순간이었다.
I'd hate that too.
나도 그건 싫다.
Right away. I'd break up right away.
곧. 나는 즉시 헤어질 것입니다.
Then a boyfriend who's nice to his female friends?
그렇다면 여자친구에게 잘해주는 남자친구는?
- Nice to them? - Yes.
- 반가워요? - 예.
How nice?
얼마나 좋은가요?
Really sweet.
정말 달콤해요.
Gives them a jacket—
그들에게 재킷을 줍니다—
I totally hate that! I'll break up immediately.
난 그거 정말 싫어! 당장 헤어지겠습니다.
Got it. Okay.
알았어요. 좋아요.
Then what about a boyfriend who thinks
그렇다면
that some other girl is cute?
다른 여자가 귀엽다고?
I seriously totally hate that.
나는 그것을 진심으로 싫어합니다.
She wasn't joking back then.
그 당시 그녀는 농담을 한 것이 아니었습니다.
There was a time when we made more than 20 dislikes a day.
하루에 싫어요가 20개 이상 나오던 시절도 있었습니다.
Ah, I remember those days.
아, 그 시절이 생각나네요.
All right, all right.
알았어, 알았어.
All the dislikes of dating are all made from back then.
연애에 대한 싫은 건 다 그때부터 만들어진 거다.
There are so many!
너무 많아요!
I hate that.
나는 그것을 싫어한다.
What's going on?
무슨 일이야?
Why is there suddenly thunder and lighting?
왜 갑자기 천둥과 번개가 치는가?
Love?
사랑?
What's up?
무슨 일이야?
Why is the weather suddenly like that?
날씨가 갑자기 왜 이래?
It's Christmas Eve but why the thunder and lightning—
크리스마스 이브인데 왜 천둥과 번개가 치는가?
Dislike Cell, find me some memos.
셀이 싫어요 메모 좀 찾아주세요.
Huh? What memos?
뭐? 무슨 메모요?
All the dislikes related to dating.
데이트와 관련된 모든 싫어함.
Sorry, there are too many.
죄송합니다. 너무 많습니다.
Are you talking about this?
이것에 대해 이야기하고 있습니까?
"I hate it when my boyfriend thinks another woman is cute!"
"내 남자친구가 다른 여자를 귀엽다고 생각하는 건 정말 싫다!"
- I hate it! I hate it! - That's right. Give it to me.
- 싫어! 싫어! - 좋아요. 나에게 주세요.
Huh? What are you doing?!
뭐? 뭐하세요?!
As I've lived my life, I've found that a person's feelings don't work like this.
제가 살아오면서 사람의 감정은 이렇게 작용하지 않는다는 걸 깨달았어요.
I mean, I ...
내 말은, 난...
I really thought I wouldn't see him again.
나는 정말로 그 사람을 다시는 볼 수 없을 것이라고 생각했다.
I'm also so... I'm so confused.
나도... 너무 혼란스러워.
I really ... I...
난 정말... 난...
I...I really like you, Miss Writer.
저...정말 좋아해요, 작가님.
I'm sorry that I had those kinds of thoughts.
제가 그런 생각을 해서 미안해요.
I also sometimes think that a man is handsome when I see them.
저도 가끔 보면 남자가 잘생겼다는 생각이 들 때가 있어요.
So I can understand it.
그래서 나는 그것을 이해할 수 있다.
Is that a reason for him to move?
그게 그가 이사하는 이유인가요?
Because you confessed your feelings?
감정을 고백했기 때문에?
That's a really absurd misunderstanding.
정말 터무니없는 오해네요.
Miss Da Eun, you really are very young.
다은씨 정말 어리시네요.
You really are a kid.
당신은 정말 어린 아이입니다.
Take care.
잘 지내세요.
I'll say goodbye in advance, because I think it will be difficult for us meet again.
우리 다시 만나긴 힘들 것 같아서 미리 인사할게요.
It's understandable.
이해할 수 있습니다.
So I'm going to pretend that I don't know.
그래서 저는 모르는 척 하려고 합니다.
When did you start liking me?
언제부터 나를 좋아하기 시작했어요?
I don't really remember.
나는 정말로 기억하지 못한다.
How can you not remember that?
어떻게 그걸 기억하지 못해요?
I don't know exactly when it was.
정확히 언제였는지 모르겠어요.
At some point, I just started to care about a woman named Kim Yumi.
어느 순간부터 김유미라는 여자에게 관심이 생기기 시작했다.
I hate it. I hate a boyfriend with a lot of secrets!
나는 그것을 싫어한다. 비밀많은 남자친구는 싫어!
Ugh, I hate it!
윽, 싫어!
Wait a second.
잠깐만요.
- Wear this on your way. - No, I'm okay! I'm okay.
- 갈 때 이걸 입고 가세요. - 아니, 난 괜찮아! 난 괜찮아.
Wear it. You'll catch a cold like that.
그것을 착용하십시오. 그런 식으로 감기에 걸리게 됩니다.
Oh... Thanks.
아... 고마워요.
I really hate a boyfriend that is also sweet to other women.
다른 여자한테도 다정하게 대해주는 남자친구는 정말 싫습니다.
I can understand everything. Yeah.
나는 모든 것을 이해할 수 있습니다. 응.
Dating isn't always easy.
데이트가 항상 쉬운 것은 아닙니다.
Hm... You're saying that you really don't hate all of that? You really, really don't?
흠... 정말 그 모든 것이 싫지 않다는 말씀이신가요? 정말, 정말 그렇지 않나요?
Yumi is an adult now!
이제 유미도 어른이 됐어요!
How can she make it in this world, if she hates everything like that?
그녀가 그런 모든 것을 싫어한다면 어떻게 이 세상을 살아갈 수 있겠습니까?
What kind of man could she date?
그녀는 어떤 남자와 데이트할 수 있을까?
Then, should we get rid of this too?
그렇다면 이것도 없애야 할까요?
Are you really okay with that?
정말 괜찮으세요?
No, I'm not!
아니요, 그렇지 않습니다!
Put this in a frame and hang it up!
액자에 넣어서 걸어두세요!
All of a sudden?
갑자기?
Yumi! The tree looks so great.
유미! 나무가 참 멋져보이네요.
That must have been difficult to do. How did you do it all alone?
그렇게 하기가 어려웠을 것입니다. 어떻게 혼자 다 했어?
We could have done it together when I got here.
내가 여기 왔을 때 함께 할 수도 있었을 텐데.
Yumi? Did she go out?
유미? 그녀는 나갔나요?
The cake is pretty.
케이크가 예쁘네요.
Yumi!
유미!
The person you have called is unavailable. Leave a message after the beep... Why isn't she picking up?
당신이 전화한 사람은 부재중입니다. 삐 소리 후에 메시지를 남겨주세요... 그녀는 왜 전화를 받지 않는 걸까요?
Why isn't she answering?
왜 그녀는 대답하지 않습니까?
Yumi?
유미?
Did she really go out?
그 사람 정말 나갔나요?
The person you have called is unavailable. Leave a message after the beep...
당신이 전화한 사람은 부재중입니다. 삐 소리 후에 메시지를 남겨주세요...
Calling Yumi
유미에게 전화걸기
Why isn't she answering the phone?
그녀는 왜 전화를 받지 않는 걸까요?
What in the world happened?
도대체 무슨 일이 일어난 걸까요?
Yumi.
유미.
What are you doing here? You're not answering the phone either.
여기서 뭐하는거야? 당신도 전화를 받지 않네요.
Did you lose your cellphone?
휴대폰을 잃어버렸나요?
No, it's right here.
아니요, 바로 여기 있어요.
Then why didn't you answer it?
그럼 왜 대답하지 않았나요?
I was going...
가려고 했는데...
to call you.
당신에게 전화하기 위해.
I was just about to.
막 그럴 참이었는데.
Why did you bring your luggage with you?
짐은 왜 가지고 왔나요?
Yumi.
유미.
Is something wrong?
뭔가 문제가 있나요?
Ba Bi.
바비.
I have something to ask you.
물어볼 게 있어요.
Please answer me seriously this time. Don't brush it off with a smile.
이번엔 진지하게 대답해주세요. 웃으면서 털어내지 마세요.
What's wrong?
무슨 일이야?
Why did you suddenly decide to move?
갑자기 이사를 결심한 이유는 무엇인가요?
I told you earlier.
내가 아까 말했잖아.
The commute is too hard, and the airport is far away.
출퇴근길이 너무 힘들고, 공항도 멀다.
Is it because of Da Eun?
다은 때문인가?
Because Da Eun confessed her feelings to you?
다은이가 자신의 마음을 고백했기 때문에?
I really hate a boyfriend who gets swayed by another woman even for just a moment.
나는 잠시라도 다른 여자에게 휘둘리는 남자친구를 정말 싫어한다.
This one I can't concede to. This one ...
이건 제가 인정할 수 없습니다. 이건 ...
is Yumi's number one dating rule.
유미의 연애 1순위 원칙이다.
Episode 26 The Second Christmas
26화 두 번째 크리스마스
Bulletin board for the surrounding people
주변 사람들을 위한 게시판
Nice to meet you. I'm Team Leader Yu Ba Bi.
만나서 반가워요. 저는 팀장 유바비 입니다.
- Nice to meet you. Let's all work well together. - Hello.
- 만나서 반가워요. 모두 함께 잘 일합시다. - 안녕하세요.
It would be best to take this out.
이것을 꺼내는 것이 가장 좋을 것입니다.
I'm sorry. Sorry.
죄송합니다. 죄송합니다.
She seems to make a lot of mistakes.
그녀는 실수를 많이 하는 것 같습니다.
I'm Yu Da Eun. Hello.
저는 유다은이에요. 안녕하세요.
That's right, Miss Yu Da Eun. You live in this neighborhood?
그렇죠, 유다은씨. 이 동네에 살아요?
Yes. That tangerine orchard is my house.
예. 그 감귤 과수원이 내 집이야.
I see.
알겠어요.
Her name is Yu Da Eun. She lives in the same neighborhood.
이름은 유다은이에요. 그녀는 같은 동네에 산다.
She's the daughter of a tangerine orchard owner.
그녀는 감귤 과수원 주인의 딸입니다.
Holiday - Je Hwi
휴일 - 제휘
♫ A room without space to take a step ♫
♫ 한 발짝도 디딜 공간이 없는 방 ♫
Oh! I love this song!
오! 나는 이 노래를 좋아한다!
- Oh, you like this song? - Yes, I really, really love it!
- 아, 이 노래 좋아해요? - 네, 정말 정말 마음에 들어요!
- She gets excited often. - Is she that innocent?
- 그녀는 자주 흥분해요. - 그 사람이 그렇게 결백한가요?
See you tomorrow.
내일 봐요.
You're not getting off work yet?
아직 퇴근 안 했어?
Please go ahead. I have to finish binding these.
계속하세요. 이것들 바인딩을 끝내야 해요.
Do it when you come in the morning. It'll be more comfortable for you to ride home in my car.
아침에 오면 꼭 해보세요. 내 차를 타고 집에 가는 것이 더 편할 거예요.
No. I have to finish this before I go to feel at ease.
아니요. 마음이 편해지려면 가기 전에 이 일을 끝내야 해요.
- Good luck, then. - Goodbye.
- 그럼 행운을 빕니다. - 안녕히 가세요.
- She is diligent. - It's good that she's always bright.
- 그녀는 부지런해요. - 항상 밝아서 좋아요.
♫ While I'm on my way to collect the heart I left behind ♫
♫ 두고 온 마음을 모으러 가는 동안 ♫
Team Leader!
팀 리더!
Good morning! I brought coffee!
좋은 아침이에요! 커피를 가져왔어요!
Are you all right?!
괜찮으세요?!
She makes too many mistakes!
그녀는 실수를 너무 많이 해요!
Goodness.
선량.
- You have a cut on your chin. - Huh?
- 턱에 상처가 났어요. - 뭐?
Oh, it's okay. Oh no, what a waste of coffee.
아, 괜찮아요. 아, 아니, 커피 낭비야.
She makes too many mistakes!!!
그녀는 실수를 너무 많이 한다!!!
You're happy even though you fell?
넘어져도 행복해요?
- She's uselessly bright. - She smiles at anything. - Is she innocent or unreliable?
- 쓸데없이 밝네요. - 그녀는 무엇이든 웃는다. - 그 사람은 순진한가요, 아니면 신뢰할 수 없는가요?
- I want to take a look inside her head. - She's really useless.
- 그녀의 머리 속을 살펴보고 싶어요. - 그 사람 정말 쓸모없어요.
She's so cute.
그녀는 너무 귀여워요.
What's this? There's a cell who wrote that she's really cute.
이건 뭐죠? 정말 귀엽다고 쓴 세포가 있어요.
They must be crazy! What do they mean cute? He's got Yumi!
미친 게 분명해! 귀여워요은 무슨 뜻인가요? 그에게 유미가 있어요!
Who the heck wrote this?
도대체 누가 쓴 걸까요?
All right. Everyone get on top of their desk and close their eyes.
괜찮은. 모두들 책상 위로 올라가 눈을 감으세요.
Cell that wrote that Da Eun is cute,
다은이가 귀엽다고 쓴 셀,
raise your hand quietly.
조용히 손을 들어보세요.
If you turn yourself in right now, I'll be the only one who knows.
지금 당장 자수하시면 저만 알 겁니다.
There's no one?
아무도 없나요?
Is there really no one?
정말 아무도 없나요?
I'm really disappointed.
정말 실망했어요.
You're really not going to tell me?
정말 나한테 말 안 할 거야?
Well, it's not me.
글쎄요, 제가 아닙니다.
No one said that it was you, Love.
아무도 당신이라고 말하지 않았어요, 사랑.
That's suspicious.
의심스럽습니다.
You've only been suspecting me since earlier!
아까부터 나만 의심했잖아!
Why are you standing only in front of me?
왜 내 앞에만 서 있나요?
I told you, it's not me!
내가 말했잖아, 내가 아니라고!
The earthquake stopped.
지진이 멈췄습니다.
I knew this would happen! I won't let him off easy!
나는 이런 일이 일어날 것이라는 것을 알았습니다! 나는 그를 쉽게 놓아주지 않을 것이다!
I won't let him off easy!
나는 그를 쉽게 놓아주지 않을 것이다!
Reason!
이유!
Hey, Love!
안녕, 사랑!
You said that it's just a small tremor?!
그냥 작은 떨림이라고 하던데요?!
Look at this! The ground is split!
이것 좀 보세요! 땅이 갈라졌다!
You call this a small tremor?!
이것을 작은 떨림이라고 부르나요?!
We can move away.
우리는 떠날 수 있습니다.
What?!
무엇?!
We'll just move house. Then we won't see Da Eun at all.
우리는 그냥 집으로 이사할 거예요. 그러면 우리는 다은을 전혀 볼 수 없을 것이다.
Then there won't be any earthquakes.
그러면 지진이 일어나지 않을 것입니다.
As I thought, you were the culprit!
내 생각대로 범인은 너였어!
Why are you doing this?
왜 이러는 걸까요?
You're the one who wrote the memo that she was really cute, right?
정말 귀여웠다는 메모를 쓴 사람이 바로 당신이죠?
I just felt that she was cute for a moment!
순간적으로 귀엽다고 느꼈어요!
You just felt that she was cute for a moment?
잠시 동안 그녀가 귀엽다고 느꼈나요?
You're the love cell!
당신은 사랑 세포입니다!
The problem is that the love cell felt that she was cute!
문제는 사랑세포가 자신을 귀엽다고 느꼈다는 것!
Why did you suddenly decide to move?
갑자기 이사를 결심한 이유는 무엇인가요?
I told you earlier.
내가 아까 말했잖아.
The commute is too hard, and the airport is far away.
출퇴근길이 너무 힘들고, 공항도 멀다.
Is it because of Da Eun?
다은 때문인가?
Because Da Eun confessed her feelings to you?
다은이가 자신의 마음을 고백했기 때문에?
See? Yumi ended up figuring it out.
보다? 유미는 결국 그것을 알아냈습니다.
What are you going to do now?
이제 무엇을 할 건가요?
You said that you thought that she was cute but it was just a momentary feeling, right?
귀엽다고 생각했지만 그건 순간적인 감정이었다고 했죠?
You said the earthquake isn't a big deal, didn't you?
지진은 별 문제가 아니라고 했죠?
Do you want to say that to Yumi, too?
유미에게도 그 말을 하고 싶나요?
Why would I tell her that?
내가 왜 그녀에게 그런 말을 하겠어요?
Why? Yumi's asking!
왜? 유미가 묻는다!
Do you want to break up with Yumi?
유미랑 헤어지고 싶어?
Of course not!
물론 그렇지 않습니다!
Then just pretend you don't know.
그럼 그냥 모르는 척 하세요.
I still like Yumi as always.
나는 여전히 유미를 좋아한다.
There's no need to tell her about this feeling, too.
이 감정도 그녀에게 말할 필요가 없습니다.
- Ba Bi— - I don't know what Da Eun told you or how she said it,
- 바비— - 다은이가 무슨 말을 했는지, 어떻게 말했는지는 모르겠지만,
but she's an immature young kid.
하지만 그 아이는 아직 미성숙한 어린 아이예요.
Don't take what a young kid says to heart.
어린아이가 하는 말을 마음에 새기지 마십시오.
You're right.
당신 말이 맞아요.
But why would you move away because of what an immature young kid said?
그런데 왜 철없는 어린아이가 한 말 때문에 떠나려고 합니까?
Because it's uncomfortable either way.
왜냐면 어느 쪽이든 불편하기 때문이죠.
I might run into her again in the future
나중에 그녀를 다시 만날지도 몰라
and there could be something you might misunderstand, like now.
지금처럼 오해할 수도 있는 부분이 있을 수 있어요.
Is that the only reason?
그게 유일한 이유인가요?
That's the reason.
그것이 이유다.
Then what about you?
그렇다면 당신은 어떻습니까?
Me?
나?
Yeah.
응.
When Da Eun said that to you,
다은이가 너한테 그런 말을 했을 때,
you weren't swayed at all?
전혀 흔들리지 않았어?
Answer the question below.
아래 질문에 답하세요.
Were you swayed when Da Eun said that as she was quitting?
다은이가 퇴사하면서 그런 말을 했을 때 흔들렸나요?
1. Yeah. Truthfully, I was for just a second.
1. 응. 사실 저는 잠깐이었습니다.
2. No, not at all.
2. 아니요, 전혀 그렇지 않습니다.
It's better to be honest here.
여기서는 솔직하게 말하는 것이 좋습니다.
The answer is number one!
대답은 1위입니다!
You crazy punk!
미친 새끼야!
There's a limit to being honest!
솔직하게 말하면 한계가 있어요!
Are you determined to end the relationship?
관계를 끝내기로 결심했나요?
Who's the one who created this situation?
이런 상황을 만든 사람은 누구일까요?
If you're sorry, you should at least be honest!
미안하다면 적어도 솔직하게 말해야 해요!
I told you that Yumi already caught on to everything!
유미가 이미 모든 걸 파악했다고 말했잖아요!
I just felt that she was cute for a second.
순간적으로 그녀가 귀엽다고 느꼈어요.
I was only swayed for a moment! It was really just a short moment!
나는 잠시 흔들렸을 뿐이야! 정말 짧은 순간이었죠!
Why are you trying to tell Yumi that?
왜 유미에게 그런 말을 하려는 거죠?
Yumi is asking!
유미가 묻는다!
She's asking him to answer honestly!
그녀는 그에게 솔직하게 대답해 달라고 요청하고 있습니다!
Guys, hold on.
여러분, 잠깐만요.
We've already got this question wrong!
우리는 이미 이 질문을 틀렸습니다!
What?!
무엇?!
This is...
이것은...
Answer in 0.1 seconds.
0.1초 안에 대답하세요.
This question has a time limit.
이 질문에는 시간 제한이 있습니다.
♫ I'm right here ♫
♫ 나 바로 여기 있어 ♫
♫ I won't change ♫
♫ 난 변하지 않을 거야 ♫
♫ I know what you want me to say ♫
♫ 당신이 내가 무슨 말을 하고 싶은지 알아요 ♫
As you date,
데이트하면서
you end up learning more about yourself than your partner.
결국 당신은 파트너보다 자신에 대해 더 많이 배우게 됩니다.
♫ I'll answer ♫
♫ 내가 대답할게 ♫
Today is our one-year anniversary.
오늘은 우리의 1주년 기념일입니다.
I was planning to give it to you tomorrow because it seemed like you forgot about it.
잊어버린 것 같아서 내일 주려고 했어요.
There's something I forgot to tell you when we were on the phone earlier.
아까 통화할 때 깜빡 잊은 게 있어요.
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
I love you.
사랑해요.
♫ While walking at dawn ♫
♫ 새벽을 걷는 동안 ♫
Me, too.
저도요.
♫ stop wherever your toes touch ♫
♫ 발가락이 닿는 곳마다 멈춰라 ♫
What about medicine?
의학은 어떻습니까?
I took it. ♫ With a dream, waves and the sand ♫
나는 그것을 가져갔다. ♫ 꿈과 파도 그리고 모래와 함께 ♫
I'm saying that we should date.
우리 데이트하자고 말하는 거야.
♫ I am breaking and scattering everyday ♫
♫ 나는 매일 부서지고 흩어진다 ♫
♫ A minor romance, my own festival ♫
♫ 소소한 로맨스, 나만의 축제 ♫
Ba Bi.
바비.
♫ Oh love, Will this love ♫
♫ 오 사랑아, 이런 사랑이 있을까 ♫
Let's break up.
헤어지자.
♫ which fills a small fist ♫
♫ 작은 주먹 하나를 채우는 ♫
♫ If it can make you happy ♫
♫ 그것이 당신을 행복하게 만들 수 있다면 ♫
♫ I can become used to being alone ♫
♫ 나는 혼자 있는 것에 익숙해질 수 있어요 ♫
♫ That's fine with me. ♫
♫ 난 괜찮아요. ♫
Total dating period:
총 데이트 기간:
One year, one month, 17 days.
1년, 한 달, 17일.
Yumi's fourth official relationship.
유미의 네 번째 공식 연애.
The relationship has end—
관계는 끝났습니다—
That feeling meant nothing.
그 느낌은 아무 의미가 없었습니다.
I didn't tell you because that feeling meant nothing.
그 느낌은 아무 의미가 없었기 때문에 말하지 않았습니다.
And I was going to move
그리고 난 이사하려고 했어
because I was worried that something like this might happen.
이런 일이 일어날까봐 걱정이 되었기 때문입니다.
I'm sorry for hurting you, Yumi.
상처줘서 미안해, 유미.
But it's in the past.
그러나 그것은 과거의 일입니다.
And really, nothing happened.
그리고 실제로는 아무 일도 일어나지 않았습니다.
Nothing happened, really.
정말 아무 일도 일어나지 않았습니다.
Dislike, did you put the memo up from earlier?
싫어요 아까 메모 올려두었나요?
Here it is! What do you think?
여기 있습니다! 어떻게 생각하나요?
I made the frame myself and hung it up!
액자를 직접 만들어서 걸어두었어요!
I really hate a boyfriend who gets swayed by another woman even for just a moment.
나는 잠시라도 다른 여자에게 휘둘리는 남자친구를 정말 싫어한다.
I did it because the number one rule is really important.
제가 그렇게 한 이유는 첫 번째 규칙이 정말 중요하기 때문입니다.
- Wait, what are you doing right now?! - He's sincerely apologizing.
- 잠깐, 지금 뭐하는 거야?! - 진심으로 사과하고 있어요.
Throw that away.
그거 버리세요.
What kind of rules are so fickle?
어떤 규칙이 그렇게 변덕스럽나요?
I hate it!
싫어!
Yumi...
유미...
I love you.
사랑해요.
I never want to break up with you.
나는 결코 당신과 헤어지고 싶지 않습니다.
Don't go.
가지 마세요.
It's an earthquake! An earthquake!
지진이다! 지진!
Yumi is wavering!
유미가 흔들리고 있어요!
Hey, what are you doing? Hurry up and give the verdict!
이봐, 뭐하는 거야? 서둘러서 판결을 내리세요!
You know, you do the slamming thing!
알다시피, 당신은 슬래밍을 하고 있어요!
O-o-okay.
오오오오오오오오오오오오오오오오오오오오오오오오오오오오오
Even so, it's too late! Ba Bi is guilty!
그래도 너무 늦었어! 바비는 유죄다!
That's hot!
정말 덥네요!
He told her everything honestly. He's apologetic.
그는 그녀에게 모든 것을 솔직하게 말했습니다. 그는 사과했습니다.
He said that he still loves Yumi as always.
그는 여전히 유미를 사랑한다고 말했다.
Can't that happen to a person once in their life?
사람이 일생에 한 번은 그런 일을 당할 수는 없을까?
Hey! So you're telling us to forgive him?
여기요! 그럼 우리한테 그 사람을 용서하라고 말하는 겁니까?
How innocent are we?
우리는 얼마나 결백한가?
Can't we understand at least this much?
이 정도는 이해할 수 없을까?
Isn't giving him at least one more chance the adult thing to do?
그에게 한 번이라도 더 기회를 주는 것이 어른이 할 수 있는 일이 아닌가?
Yumi.
유미.
Don't leave like this.
이대로 떠나지 마세요.
Today is
오늘은
Christmas Eve.
크리스마스 이브.
Huh?
뭐?
Yumi, today's Christmas Eve.
유미 씨, 오늘은 크리스마스 이브예요.
So let's just ...
그럼 그냥...
just ...
그냥 ...
let's just pretend we can't win, you guys.
그냥 못 이긴 척 하자, 너희들.
- Although, our heart may be giving in and you all may be confused ... - Look at that.
- 그래도 우리 마음은 굴복하고 여러분 모두는 혼란스러울 수도 있겠지만... - 저것 좀 보세요.
Love, more than that, you ...
사랑, 그 이상으로 당신은...
- There are horns growing on your head. - Yeah.
- 머리에 뿔이 자라고 있어요. - 응.
And they're getting bigger.
그리고 그들은 점점 더 커지고 있습니다.
What's happening?
무슨 일이야?
Why do you have horns?
왜 뿔이 있나요?
Love, are you okay?
사랑아, 괜찮아?
It's a skull!
해골이에요!
Yumi. First, let's go home and–
유미. 우선 집에 가서-
Ba Bi.
바비.
Even if we keep dating like we are now,
지금처럼 계속 연애를 해도
I don't think I can treat you the way I used to
예전처럼 당신을 대할 수 없을 것 같아요
as if nothing happened.
마치 아무 일도 일어나지 않은 것처럼.
Yu Ba Bi was someone really special.
유바비는 정말 특별한 사람이었다.
He was someone who made my heart flutter the most and someone I dreamed of.
그 사람은 내 마음을 가장 설레게 했던 사람이자, 내가 꿈꾸던 사람이었다.
♫ When you're about to be caught ♫
♫ 당신이 잡히려고 할 때 ♫
♫ When you melt in a teacup ♫
♫ 찻잔에 녹을 때 ♫
♫ A lovely smile can't contain everything. ♫
♫ 사랑스러운 미소는 모든 것을 담을 수 없습니다. ♫
♫ It makes me feel anxious ♫
♫ 그것은 나를 불안하게 만든다 ♫
♫ Don't hide anymore ♫
♫ 더 이상 숨지 마세요 ♫
♫ the light hidden in a corner of your heart ♫
♫ 마음 한구석에 숨겨진 빛 ♫
At the end of a dream-like relationship
꿈같은 연애 끝에
Love was left with only rage.
사랑은 분노만 남았습니다.
♫ I want to become drops of rain knocking on the window ♫
♫ 나는 창문을 두드리는 빗방울이 되고 싶어 ♫
Even though she felt like she was going to burst, she held it in. ♫  and whisper love ♫
터질 것 같은 느낌에도 그녀는 참았다. ♫ 그리고 사랑을 속삭여 ♫
Dating, damn you!
데이트, 젠장!
This damned love affair!
이 빌어먹을 연애!
I'm telling you it is exasperating!
나는 그것이 짜증난다고 말하고 있다!
Love!
사랑!
That's hot!
정말 덥네요!
Detective! Love is totally crazy!
형사! 사랑은 완전히 미쳤어!
What do we do now?!
이제 우리는 무엇을 할까요?!
Don't worry. I just found a way.
괜찮아요. 방금 방법을 찾았습니다.
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
We just need to kick out Love from the prime cell position.
우리는 프라임 셀 위치에서 Love를 쫓아내기만 하면 됩니다.
Because Love is the prime cell, she has that strong power.
사랑은 원세포이기 때문에 그만큼 강한 힘을 가지고 있습니다.
We need to give the prime cell position to another cell.
프라임 셀 위치를 다른 셀에 제공해야 합니다.
To whom?
누구에게?
The principle of succession.
승계의 원칙.
The cell in the second highest order of current priorities
현재 우선순위에서 두 번째로 높은 셀
is promoted as the next prime cell.
차기 프라임 셀로 승격됩니다.
Since the love that was in the first position is gone,
첫 번째 위치에 있던 사랑이 사라졌기 때문에
the one in the second position who is to succeed as the prime cell is ...
프라임 셀로 성공할 두 번째 위치에 있는 사람은 ...
Me? I'm the next prime cell?
나? 내가 다음 프라임 셀인가?
Writer is?
작가는?
Really? I never imagined this.
정말? 나는 이것을 상상하지 못했습니다.
Says who? I'm the prime cell!
누가 말했어? 나는 프라임 셀이다!
I am Yumi's prime cell!
나는 유미의 프라임 셀이다!
The most important thing to Yumi is me, Love!
유미에게 가장 중요한 건 바로 나, 사랑!
If you want to take my position ...
내 입장을 취하고 싶다면...
go ahead and try!
가서 시도해 보세요!
Pass it on to her.
그녀에게 전달하세요.
Yu-Yumi.
유유미.
Yumi appeared in the village!
마을에 유미가 나타났다!
Yumi!
유미!
Yumi's here.
유미가 왔어요.
Love, I know you've been working hard.
사랑해요, 당신이 열심히 일했다는 걸 알아요.
Yu-Yumi.
유유미.
But I don't want to live being in a blazing rage.
하지만 나는 타오르는 분노 속에 살고 싶지 않습니다.
The reason dating was my number one priority was that I thought that if I were in a relationship,
연애를 최우선으로 생각한 이유는 연애를 하면
I would be happy. That's how I decided it.
나는 행복할 것이다. 나는 그렇게 결정했다.
Give the prime cell position to Writer.
Writer에 프라임 셀 위치를 지정합니다.
Who cares if I'm not in a relationship?
내가 연애 중이 아니면 누가 신경쓰나요?
What I want is always the same.
내가 원하는 것은 언제나 똑같다.
♫ The day starts as if being shoved ♫
♫ 밀린 듯 하루가 시작된다 ♫
♫ I spend the day constantly acting fearless ♫
♫ 나는 끊임없이 두려움 없이 행동하며 하루를 보낸다 ♫
♫ and before I know it the night arrives ♫
♫ 그리고 내가 알기도 전에 밤이 찾아온다 ♫
♫ The dark night ♫
♫ 어두운 밤 ♫
♫ The sadness which I've endured all day ♫
♫ 하루종일 견뎌온 슬픔 ♫
I just ♫ arrives like a routine ♫
난 그냥 ♫ 일상처럼 도착해 ♫
want to be happy.
행복하고 싶다.
♫ I hide in the middle of nowhere ♫
♫ 나는 외딴 곳에 숨어 있어요 ♫
♫ Pathetically with a thud landing on the floor I am crying ♫
♫ 한심하게도 바닥에 쿵 하는 소리를 내며 울고 있어요 ♫
♫ Today too ♫
♫ 오늘도 ♫
♫ Dark feelings will be passed tonight ♫
♫ 오늘밤 어두운 감정은 지나가리라 ♫
Yumi's Cells 2 Preview
유미의 세포들 2 미리보기
Do you believe in fate?
당신은 운명을 믿나요?
- What are you talking about?
- 무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
Ku Woong Games CEO Gu Wung Hey! Hey! Hey!
구웅게임즈 대표 구웅 이봐! 여기요! 여기요!
- Writer Kim Yumi. - Try contacting her.
- 김유미 작가. - 그 사람한테 연락해 보세요.
There's no reason to.
그럴 이유가 없습니다.
Love, are you home?
자기야, 집에 있어?
Do you believe in fate?
당신은 운명을 믿나요?
Because I really look up to you. Hyeong Wung.
왜냐하면 나는 정말로 당신을 존경하기 때문입니다. 웅형.
I'm sorry but "My Love Muse" has been sold out.
죄송합니다. '나의 사랑 뮤즈'는 매진되었습니다.
It's sold out?
매진됐나요?
Can you give me a ride to the subway station?
지하철 역까지 태워다 주실 수 있나요?
Do you believe in fate?
당신은 운명을 믿나요?